American Philosophical Society Archives. Record Group IIe. 1845-1865 APS.Archives.IIe APS.Archives.IIe
American Philosophical Society
- Papers
  - Letter to Isaac Lea, Jan. 22, 1850; 6-1/2x4; Prescott, William Hickling, 1796-1859
    Boston, A.L.S. 4p., end. Presents, as gift from the author, Don Lucas Alaman, the three volume History of Mexico.
  - Letter to the Secretary of the A.P.S., Jan. 29, 1850; 10x8; American Academy of Arts and Sciences
    Boston, Printed letter filled in in ms.S.: Asa Gray. 1p., end. Forwards publications.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Philadelphia, Feb. 1, 1850; 10-3/4x8-1/2; Königlich Bayerische Akademie der Wissenschaften
    Munich, Printed L.filled in in ms.S.: Wiedmann. 1p.,end.: C.B.T[rego]. In German. Thanks for Proceedings and Transactions.
  - Letter to Cha[rle]s B. Trego, Philadelphia, Feb. 7, 1850; 10x8; Amherst College
    A.L.S.: E. S. Snell, Libn. 1p.,end. and add. Thanks for Proceedings.
  - Letter to the Secretary of the A.P.S., Feb, 1850; 8x5; Cambridge Philosophical Society
    Cambridge, Printed letter filled in in ms.S.: C. C. Babington. 1p., end. Forwards publication.
  - Letter to the A.P.S., Feb., 1850; 10x8; U.S. Coast and Geodetic Survey
    Washington, Printed letter filled in in ms.S.: A.D.Bache. 1p., end. Forwards maps.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Philadelphia, March 4, 1850; 10-1/2x8-1/2; Akademie der Wissenschaften in Göttingen
    Göttingen, A.L.S.: J.Fr.L. Hausmann. 1p.,end.: J.F.F[isher]. Thanks for Transactions and Proceedings
  - Letter to Cha[rle]s B. Trego, March 9, 1850; 7 1/4" x 8 15/16"; Vaughan, Petty, 1788-1854
  - Letter to the Secretary of the A.P.S., March 10, 1850; 11x8-1/2; Société de géographie (France)
    Paris, L.S.: J. Cuirat. 1p., end. In French. Forwards publication.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Philadelphia, March 20, 1850; 10-1/4x8; Royal Society of London
    Printed L.filled in in ms.S.: Edward Sabine. 1p.,end.: J.F.F.[isher] and add. Thanks for Proceedings and Journal of ANS.
  - Letter to Cha[rle]s B. Trego, April 5, 1850; 7 3/8" x 9 1/4"; Vaughan, Petty, 1788-1854
    London, 1 p., address and endorsement. L.S. Is sending "the usual periodicals" by the America. Encloses account for 6.13.4.
  - Letter to Cha[rle]s B. Trego, April 8, 1850; 10x8; Beck, Theodoric Romeyn, 1791-1855
    Albany, A.L.S. 1p.,end. Wants APS publications to complete set for New York state library. On same sheet as: N.Y.state library to APS; April 8, 1850.
  - Letter to Robley Dunglison, April 8, 1850; 8-3/4x5-1/2; New Jersey Historical Society
    New Ark, Printed L.filled in in ms.S.: Sam H. Pennington. 1p.,end. Thanks for Proceedings.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Philadelphia, April 8, 1850; 10x8; New York State Library
    Albany, Printed L.filled in in ms.S.: T.Romeyn Beck. 1p.,end. Thanks for Proceedings. On same sheet is letter from T.R.Beck to C.B.Trego; April 8, 1850.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Philadelphia, April 9, 1850; 10x8; Harvard University
    Cambridge, Printed L.filled in in ms.S.: Jared Sparks, Pres.and Thaddeus William Harris, Libn. 1p.,end.: C.B.T[rego] and add.: Care of Robley Dunglison. Thanks for Proceedings.
  - Letter to Charles B. Trego, April 10, 1850; 10x8; Reed, William B. (William Bradford), 1806-1876
    Philadelphia, A.L.S. 1p., end. Regarding the donation of a series of numbers of the "Fauna Antiqua" to the APS.
  - Report of the committee to whom was referred a paper by [Elias] Loomis, April 16, 1850; 8" x 10"; American Philosophical Society
    on the longitude of Hudson (Ohio) observatory, Philadelphia, 1 p. and endorsement. D.S.: E. Otis Kendall, John F. Frazer. Publication in Transactions recommended.
  - Letter to the Secretary of the A.P.S., April 18/30, 1850; 10-1/2x8-1/2; Moskovskoe obshchestvo li︠u︡biteleĭ prirody
    Moscow, Printed letter filled in in ms.S.: Dr.Renard. 1p., end. In French. Forwards publications.
  - Letter to the American Philosophical Society, April 26, 1850; 7 7/8" x 10"; Browne, Peter A. (Peter Arrell), 1782-1860
    Philadelphia, 1 p. and endorsement. A.L.S. In re microscopic examination of hair of ancient Peruvians and modern Indians. See Pro., V, 145.
  - Letter to ----, April 30, 1850; 8 1/2" x 10 15/16"; Hammer-Purgstall, Joseph, Frieherr von, 1774-1856
    Vienna, 3 pp. and endorsements. A.L.S. Transmits a complete set of the Vienna Review. Also sends "separate copies of my academical labours." See Pro., V, 171. FILM403 FRAME114
  - Letter to C[harles] B. Trego, May 3, 1850; 10-1/2x8-1/2; Bataviaasche genootschap von kunsten en wetenschappen
    Amsterdam, [read] Printed L.filled in in ms.S.: W.Vrolik 1p.,end. In French. Thanks for Transactions and Proceedings
  - Letter to Cha[rle]s B. Trego, May 4, 1850; 7 3/8" x 9 3/16"; Vaughan, Petty, 1788-1854
  - Letter to Charles B. Trego, May 15, 1850; 8" x 9 7/8"; Beck, Theodoric Romeyn, 1791-1855
    Albany, 1 p. and endorsement. A.L.S. Acknowledges the receipt of the 13th number of vol. I of ----?
  - Letter to Cha[rle]s B. Trego, May 30, 1850; 4 1/2" x 7"; Vaughan, Petty, 1788-1854
    London, 3 pp. and endorsement. L.S. Acknowledges receipt of A.P.S. Proceedings, V, no. 44. Death of Mr. William Vaughan on May 5, aged 98.
  - Letter to the Secretary of the A.P.S., June 1, 1850; 7 15/16" x 10"; Bowditch, Henry I. (Henry Ingersoll), 1808-1892
    Boston, 1 p., address and endorsement. A.L.S. Wishes to know what to do with a package for the A.P.S. at the American Academy of Arts and Sciences.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, June 1, 1850; 10x8; Connecticut Historical Society
    Hartford, Printed L.filled in in ms.S.: Chas.Hosmer. 1p.,end.: J.F.F[isher]. Thanks for Proceedings.
  - Letter to Cha[rle]s B. Trego, June 5, 1850; 7 1/4" x 8 3/4"; Vaughan, Petty, 1788-1854
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, June 6, 1850; 14x9; Geological Society of London
    Printed L.filled in in ms.S.: Wm. J. Hamilton. 1p.,end.: C.B.T[rego], add. Thanks for Proceedings.
  - Letter to Charles B. Trego, Secretary of A.P.S., June 24, 1850; 7 7/8" x 9 7/8"; Redfield, John Howard, 1815-1895
    New York, 1 p., address and endorsement. A.L.S. Acknowledges receipt of books. Has arranged for forwarding of box of books per ship Nord America to the A.P.S.
  - Letter to Cha[rle]s B. Trego, July 11, 1850; 7 3/8" x 9"; Vaughan, Petty, 1788-1854
    London, 1 p., address and endorsement. L.S. Is sending designated journals to the A.P.S. by the Philadelphia packet of July 12.
  - Letter to the A.P.S., July 20, 1850; 13-1/2x8-1/2; Belgium. Ministére de l'intérieur
    Brussels, L.S.: Quételet. 1p., end. In French. Forwards publications.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Philadelphia, July 20, 1850; 10x8; Royal Geographical Society (Great Britain)
    Printed L.filled in in ms.S.: Norton Shaw. 2p.,end.: C.B.T[rego] and add. Thanks for Proceedings. Lists numbers wanting.
  - Letter to Cha[rle]s B. Trego, August 12, 1850; 7 1/4" x 8 3/4"; Vaughan, Petty, 1788-1854
    London, 1 p., address and endorsement. L. Is sending designated journals to the A.P.S. "by the Philadelphia Packet of this day."
  - Proceedings of the board of trustees, August 15, 1850; 8 3/8" x 10 13/16"; University of Nashville
    Thursday morning, 1 p. and endorsement. Pr.D.S.: Philip Lindsley, President of the University and of the Board of Trustees. Resolutions adopted upon the death of Professor Gerard Troost. See Pro., V, 163.
  - Letter to the A.P.S., Aug.15, 1850; 11x8-1/2; Deutsche Akademie der Wissenschaften zu Berlin
    Berlin, Printed letter filled in in ms.S.: Trendelenburg. 1p., end. In German. Forwards publications.
  - Letter to B[enjamin] W. Richards, September 4, 1850; 5" x 8"; Smith, J. Jay (John Jay), 1798-1881
    Treasurer of A.P.S., [Philadelphia], 1 p., address and endorsement. A.N.S. Calls attention to unpaid bond given by the A.P.S. to the Athenian Institute for money lent. See: Resolution of Athenian Institute, May 12, 1846.
  - Letter to Cha[rle]s B. Trego, Sept. 7, 1850; 10x8; Gould, Benjamin Apthorp, 1824-1896
    Cambridge, A.L.S. 1p., end. Sends volume to the Society from Professor Schumacher.
  - Letter to Cha[rle]s B. Trego, September 12, 1850; 7 1/4" x 8 3/4"; Vaughan, Petty, 1788-1854
    London, 1 p., address and endorsement. L.S. Is sending designated journals to the A.P.S. by the Saranack.
  - Letter to the Corresponding Secretary of the A.P.S., September 20, 1850; 8" x 10"; Graham, J. D. (James Duncan), 1799-1865
    Washington, 3 pp. and endorsements. A.L.S. Wishes an attested copy of his diploma of membership in the A.P.S., as original was burned. Granted. See Pro., V, 176.
  - Letter to R[obert] M. Patterson, September 23, 1850; 7 1/4" x 8 7/8"; Richards, Benjamin Wood, 1797-1851
    President of A.P.S., Philadelphia, 1 p. A.L.S. Requests Mr. Patterson to be present to affix the seal of the Society to the deed of release of the Dickinson ground rent.
  - Letter to the Secretary of the A.P.S., Sept. 26/Oct. 8, 1850; 10-1/2x8-1/2; Moskovskoe obshchestvo li︠u︡biteleĭ prirody
    Moscow, Printed letter filled in in ms.S.: Dr.Renard. 1p., end. In French. Forwards publication.
  - Letter to Charles B. Trego, October 10, 1850; 7 3/4" x 9 5/8"; Gaskill, Edward
    Secretary of A.P.S. Philadelphia, 1p., address and endorsement. A.L.S. Proposes to sell to the A.P.S. a copy of The Natural History of the State of New York. See Pro., V, 164.
  - Letter to the Secretary of the A.P.S., Oct. 10, 1850; 10x8; Kungl. Svenska vetenskapsakademien
    Stockholm, L.S.: Wahlberg. 1p., end. In French. Sends medal struck in memory of Baron Berzelius to the APS.
  - Letter to Cha[rle]s B. Trego, October 10, 1850; 8" x 10"; Vaughan, Petty, 1788-1854
    London, 1 p., address and endorsement. L. Is sending designated journals to the A.P.S. "by the Philadelphia packet of the 12th Instant."
  - Letter to the President of the A.P.S., Oct. 12, 1850; 9-1/2x7-1/2; Santarém, Manuel Francisco de Barros e Sousa, Visconde de, 1791-1856
    Paris, A.L.S. 1p., end. In French. Donates copy of his work of the middle ages to the APS.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Philadelphia, Oct. 16, 1850; 10x8; Literary and Philosophical Society of Manchester
    Printed L.filled in in ms.S.: James P. Joule and Edwd.Wm. Binney. 1p.,end.: C.B.T[rego] and add. Thanks for proceedings.
  - Letter to the A.P.S., Oct. 18, 1850; 10x8; Kungl. Svenska vetenskapsakademien
    Stockholm, Printed letter filled in in ms.S.: Wahlberg. 1p., end. In French. Presents publication.
  - Letter to the Secretary of the A.P.S., Oct. 31, 1850; 12-1/2x8-1/2; Amsterdam. K. nederlandsche instituut van wetenschappen, letterkunde en schoone kunsten
    Amsterdam, Printed letter filled in in ms.S.: W. Vrolik. 1p., end. In French. Forwards publications.
  - Letter to Cha[rle]s B. Trego, November 7, 1850; 8" x 10"; Vaughan, Petty, 1788-1854
    London, 1 p., address and endorsement. L.S. Is sending package of periodicals to the A.P.S. The state of his health forces him to request the A.P.S. to find another agent in England.
  - Letter to the American Philosophical Society, November 18, 1850; 5 1/4" x 8"; Bernhisel, John M. (John Milton), 1799-1881
    New York, 1 p. and endorsement. A.L.S. Encloses a printed circular (missing) requesting contributions of books for a library in Utah. See Pro., V, 169.
  - Letter to Ch[arles] B. Trego, November 21, 1850; 8 1/4" x 10 5/8"; Bossange, Hector, 1795-1884
    Paris, 2 pp., address and endorsement. Has "taken the necessary steps to procure" certain issues of Comptes rendus for the A.P.S. Encloses account for fr. 64.05.
  - Letter to the A.P.S., Dec. 2, 1850; 10x7-1/2; Ferris, Benjamin, 1780-1867
    Wilmington, read, A.L.S. 1p. and add., end. Offers seven works upon Seneca Indians and one on "Original Settlements on...the Delaware River" to the APS.
  - Letter to C[harles] B. Trego, December 5, 1850; 4 3/4" x 7 1/4"; Vaughan, Petty, 1788-1854
    London, 1 p. address and endorsement. L.S. Advises of package sent by packet of the 12th. inst. Preparations for exhibition of 1851.
  - Letter to Charles B. Trego, December 14, 1850; 7 7/8" x 10"; D. Appleton and Company
    New York, 1 p., address and endorsement. L. Requests A.P.S. to inform Mr. B. L. C. Wailes of Jefferson College, Washington, Mississippi, of the cost of a set of Transactions.
  - Letter to the A.P.S., Dec. 27, 1850; 10x8; U.S. Coast and Geodetic Survey
    Washington, Printed letter filled in in ms.S.: A. D. Bache. 1p., end. Sends maps to the APS.
  - Report of committee on best mode of employing $200.00 to be placed at the disposal of George Ord for purchase of books in Paris, 1850; 12x7-1/2; American Philosophical Society
    [ca.]. D. 1p. and end.
  - Letter to the Secretary of the A.P.S., Jan. 1, 1851; 8x5; Cambridge Philosophical Society
  - Report of the committee to whom was referred a paper by Mr. [M. Fisher] Longstreth, January 8, 1851; 7 5/8" x 9 7/8"; American Philosophical Society
    "On the accuracy of the tabular longitudes of the moon," Philadelphia, 1 p. and endorsement. D.S.: E. Otis Kendall, John F. Frazer, John Downes. Publication in Transactions recommended.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Jan. 9, 1851; 9-3/4x7-3/4; Boston Athenaeum
    Boston, Printed L.filled in in ms.S.: Thos. G. Cary, Pres.and Charles Folsom, Libn. 1p.,end.: J.F.F[razer]. Thanks for Proceedings.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Philadelphia, Jan. 9, 1851; 10x8; Harvard University
    Cambridge, Printed L.filled in in ms.S.: Jared Sparks, Pres.and Thaddeus William Harris, Libn. 1p.,end.: C.B.T[rego] and add., end. Thanks for Proceedings.
  - Letter to Cha[rle]s B. Trego, January 10, 1851; 7 1/2" x 9 1/4"; Vaughan, Petty, 1788-1854
    London, 1 p., address and endorsement. L.S. Is sending designated journals to the A.P.S. by the Philadelphia packet. Death of Professor [H. C.] Schumacher.
  - Report of the committee to whom was referred Dr. [Joseph] Leidy's paper, January 14, 1851; 4 3/4" x 7"; American Philosophical Society
    "On the organization of the genus Gregarina of Dufour," Philadelphia, 1 p. and endorsement. D.S.: Samuel George Morton, Isaac Lea, Isaac Hays. Publication recommended.
  - Letter to R[obley] Dunglison, Philadelphia, Jan. 15, 1851; 8-3/4x5-1/2; New Jersey Historical Society
    Newark, Printed L.filled in in ms.S.: Sam. H. Pennington. 1p.,end.: C.B.T[rego] and add. Thanks for the Proceedings.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Jan. 15, 1851; 10x8; New York State Library
    Albany, Printed L. filled in in ms. S.: T.Romeyn Beck. 1p., end.: C.B.T[rego]. Thanks for Proceedings.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Jan. 15, 1851; 10-3/4x8-1/4; Historical Society of Pennsylvania
    Philadelphia, A.L.S.: William Duane. 1p.,end.: C.B. T[rego]. Thanks for Proceedings.
  - Letter to Cha[rle]s B. Trego, January 17, 1851; 4 1/2" x 7 5/8"; Richards, Benjamin Wood, 1797-1851
    [Philadelphia], 1 p. D.S.: for B. W. Richards, Treas. Jno. F. James. Receipt for $105 annual contributions to A.P.S. from listed members thereof.
  - Letter to the Secretary of the A.P.S., February 2, 1851; 7 3/4" x 9 3/4"; Gould, Benjamin Apthorp, 1824-1896
    Cambridge, 1 p. and endorsement. A.L.S. Announcing the death of Professor H. C. Schumacher, of Altona, on December 28, 1850. See Pro., V, 181.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Feb. 5, 1851; 10x8; Connecticut Historical Society
    Hartford, Printed L.filled in in ms.S.: Chas. Hosmer. 1p.,end.: C.B.T[rego]. Thanks for Proceedings.
  - Letter to the A.P.S., Feb. 6/18, 1851; Wrontschenko, Comte
  - Report of the committee to whom was referred Dr. [Joseph] Leidy's paper entitled, February 7, 1851; 7 3/8" x 9"; American Philosophical Society
    "Some observations on Nematoidea imperfecta," [Philadelphia], 1 p. and endorsement. D.S.: Isaac Hays, Isaac Lea, W. S. W. Rusohenberger. Publication in. Transactions recommended.
  - Letter to Cha[rle]s B. Trego, February 7, 1851; 7 3/4" x 9 3/4"; Vaughan, Petty, 1788-1854
    London, 2 pp., address and endorsement. L.S. Concerning the late [William] Vaughan. Recommends Mr. Sandford, of Edwards, Sandford and Company, as agent for the A.P.S.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Philadelphia, Feb. 9, 1851; 10-1/2x8-1/2; Akademie der Wissenschaften in Göttingen
    Göttingen, A.L.S.: Hausmann. 1p.,end.: C.B.T[rego]. Thanks for Proceedings.
  - Letter to John Vaughan, February 16, 1851; 3 15/16" x 6 3/8"; Hazard, Ebenezer, 1744-1817
    [Phila-delphia, ]. 1 p., address and endorsement. A.L.S. Forwards to the A.P.S.: a donation from the Massachusetts Historical Society. Not found May, 2011.
  - Letter to the Secretary of the A.P.S., February 17, 1851; 8" x 9 15/16"; Hill, John, Jr.
    Willimantic, Conn.,1 p. and endorsement. A.L.S. Requests a copy of the constitution and laws of the A.P.S. See Pro., V, 183.
  - List of several rare and valuable specimens of colonial paper money, Feb. 21, 1851; 10x8; Hart, Adolphus M. (Adolphus Mordecai), 1814-1879
    offered for sale; [read] D. 1p.and end. Refers to some money printed by Franklin. See APS Proceedings, V, 183. FILM54-67 FRAME 81
  - Report in reference to duties and salary of librarian, March 14, 1851; 11x9; American Philosophical Society. Library committee
    [Philadelphia] D.S.: John F. Frazer, Geo. M. Justice, and A. L. Elwyn. 4p. and end.
  - Letter to the Secretary of the A.P.S., March 18, 1851; 11x8-1/2; Flügel, J. G. (Johann Gottfried), 1788-1855
    Leipsic, L.S. 3p., end. Forwards package of books to the APS.
  - Letter to the Secretary of the A.P.S., March 24, 1851; 11x8-1/2; Hollandsche Maatschappij der Wetenschappen
    Harlem, Printed letter filled in in ms.S.: J.G.S. Van Breda. 1p., end. In french. Presents publication.
  - Letter to Charles B.Trego, March 25, 1851; 7 7/8" x 9 7/8"; Bache, A. D. (Alexander Dallas), 1806-1867
    Secretary of A.P.S., Washington, 1 p. A.L.S. Will execute wishes of the A.P.S. regarding testimonial to the merits of the late Professor [H. C.] Schumacher. Requests that diplomas be sent to him for signature.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, March 28, 1851; 10x8; Society of Antiquaries of London
    Printed L.filled in in ms.S.: J.Y.Akerman 1p.,end. Thanks for Proceedings.
  - Letter to the American Philosophical Society, April 2, 1851; 6 3/4" x 8 7/16"; Ward, Townsend, 1817?-1885
    Philadelphia, 1 p. and endorsement. A.L.S. The Historical Society of Pennsylvania asks permission to have a copy painted of the Portrait of [John] Heckewelder belonging to the A.P.S. See Pro., V, 190.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Philadelphia, April 8, 1851; 10x8; Literary and Philosophical Society of Manchester
    Printed L.filled in in ms.S.: James P. Joule and Edwd.Wm.Binney. 1p.,end.: C.B. T[rego] and add. Thanks for Proceedings.
  - Letter to Cha[rle]s B. Trego, April 11, 1851; 7 1/4" x 8 3/4"; Vaughan, Petty, 1788-1854
    London, 1 p., address and endorsement. L.S. Is sending designated journals to the A.P.S. library.
  - Letter to the Secretary of the A.P.S., May 3, 1851; 9-1/2x8; Martínez, Juan José
    Madrid, A.L.S. 1p., end. Forwards copy of his dictionary and his edition of Mendoza's tables for navigation.
  - Letter to the A.P.S., May 6, 1851; 9x7-1/2; Royal Geological Society of Cornwall
    Penzance, L.S.: Joseph Corne. 1p., end. Forwards publications and acknowledges receipt of APS publications.
  - Letter to the A.P.S., May 6, 1851; 11 x 8-1/2; Kaiserl. Akademie der Wissenschaften in Wien
    Printed letter filled in in ms.S.: Wilhelm Braumuller. 1p. and end. In German. Presents publications.
  - Letter to the President of the A.P.S., May 13, 1851; 7 7/8" x 9 7/8"; Gourdin, William Allston
    Charleston, 1 p. and endorsement. A.L.S. Offers to sell a four volume set of John James Audubon's Birds of America to the A.P.S. FILM403 FRAME177
  - Letter to Charles B. Trego, May 15, 1851; 5" x 8"; Shippen, William, 1792-1867
    Philadelphia, 1 p. and endorsement. A.L.S. Declines membership in the A.P.S. See Pro., V, 200.
  - Letter to the A.P.S., June 4, 1851; 10-1/2x8-1/2; Kongelige Nordiske oldskriftselskab (Denmark)
    Copenhagen, L.S.: Chas. C. Rafn. 1p., end. Sends publications.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Philadelphia, June 5, 1851; 10x7-1/2; Linnean Society of London
    London, Printed L.filled in in ms.S.: John J. Bennett. 1p.,end.: C.B.T.[rego], and add. Thanks for Proceedings.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, 15/27 June, 1851; 8 1/4" x 10 1/2"; Kupfer, Adolf I︠A︡kovlevich, 1799-1865
    St. Pétersbourg, A.L.S. 3p. In French. Relative to an exchange of publications with the Observatoire physique central.
  - Letter to Charles B. Trego, June 16, 1851; 7 1/2" x 9 3/4"; Jarvis, Edward, 1803-1884
    Secretary of A.P.S., Dorchester, Mass., 2 pp. A.L.S. Is sending "several of the documents of this state and some of its towns and cities" to the A.P.S.
  - Smithsonian Institution to the American Philosophical Society, June 20, 1851; 7 7/8" x 9 7/8"; Smithsonian Institution
    Washington, 1 p. D.S.: Joseph Henry, Secretary. Presents Smithsonian Contributions to Knowledge, II, to the A.P.S.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Philadelphia, June 25, 1851; 11-1/4x9; Königlich Bayerische Akademie der Wissenschaften
    Munich, Printed L.filled in in ms.S.: Wiedmann. 2p.,end.: C.B.T[rego]. In German. Thanks for Proceedings. Forwards publications.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, London, June 25, 1851; 10-1/4x8
    Philadelphia, Printed L.filled in in ms.S.: W.H.Smyth. 1p.,end.: C.B.T[rego] and add. Thanks for Proceedings.
  - Letter to the A.P.S., July 7, 1851; 10x8-1/2; Russia. Gornyĭ departament
    St. Petersburg, Printed letter. 1p., end. In French. Forwards publication.
  - Letter to Charles B. Trego, July 10, 1851; 8" x 10"; Harvard University
    Librarian of A.P.S., Cambridge, 1 p. and address. D.S.: Jared Sparks, President. Acknowledges receipt of designated volumes of the Journal of Prison Discipline and Philanthropy.
  - Letter to Charles B. Trego, July 12, 1851; 8-1/2x7; Boston Society of Natural History
    Boston, L.S.: Ch. K. Dillaway. 2p., end. Sends publications.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Philadelphia, July 16, 1851; 10x8; Harvard University
    Cambridge, Printed L.filled in in ms.S.: Jared Sparks, Pres.and Thaddeus William Harris, Libn. 1p.,end.: E.O.K[endall] and add. Thanks for Proceedings.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, July 16, 1851; 10x7-3/4; Smithsonian Institution
    Washington, Printed L.filled in in ms.S.: Joseph Henry. 1p.,end.: C.B.T[rego]. Thanks for Proceedings.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, July 17, 1851; 10X8; American Antiquarian Society
    Worcester, A.L.S.: Sam[ue]l F. Haven. 1p.,end.: C.B.T[rego]. Thanks for Proceedings.
  - Letter to R[obley] Dunglison, July 21, 1851; 10x8; New York State Library
    Albany, Printed L.filled in in ms.S.: T.Romeyn Beck. 1p.,end.: C.B.T[regeo] Thanks for Proceedings.
  - Letter to Ch[arles] B. Trego, July 28, 1851; 8" x 10"; Greenleaf, Simon, 1783-1853
    Boston, 1 p. and address. A.L.S. Is sending a parcel of pamphlets to the library of the A.P.S. See Pro. V, 215.
  - Letter to the A.P.S., July, 1851; 8-1/2x7; Gould, Augustus A. (Augustus Addison), 1805-1866
    Boston, Printed L.S.: Augustus A. Gould and D. Humphreys Storer. 1p., end. Sends copy of Amos Binney's work on mollusks to the A.P.S.
  - Letter to the President of the A.P.S., August 14, 1851; United States. Department of State
  - Letter to the A.P.S., Aug. 15, 1851; 11x8-1/2; Deutsche Akademie der Wissenschaften zu Berlin
    Berlin, Printed form filled in in ms.S: Trendelenberg. 1p., end. In German. Forwards publications.